日本語字幕仕上げ：miraku  光荣字幕组（www.koeigame.cn）
Sera?
世良…　赤崎か？  それとも…
Or Akasaki?
Or?
What are you doing, Natsuki?! Make up your mind!
何やってんだ　夏木！  判断遅えよ！
Pass it here, Hauer!
よこせや　ハウアー！
Go make some space!
早よ　スペース作れ！
Bastard!
ここだ！
Good job, Sugie!
よ～し　いいぞ　杉江！
We stopped Osaka's attacks!
大阪の攻撃を単発で抑えたぞ！
I guess you've learnt, Sugie.
ようやく  吹っ切れたみたいだな　スギ
I guess now the problem is him.
で　問題は　あいつか
You mean Natsuki?
夏木ですか？
Maybe it's because I said that to him before the game.
試合前に　あんな事  言っちゃったからかなぁ
Huh? What did you say to Natsuki?
あんな事？
何を言ったんですか？　夏木に
Hmm?
I told him...
お前には　フォワードとしての  決心が足りないって言った
that he lacks resolve as a forward.
United we stand,Fly a flag 風を受け止めて
United we stand, Fly a flag!
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand,Fly a flag たなびけ勝利のflag
United we stand, Fly a flag!
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けていて
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
for the right
For the right! Hold on tight!
hold on tight
my story…
My story...
forever
Forever...
Good. I'm good.
悪くない…
悪くないぞ
Just now, I took a while to decide on my next move.
さっきは　次のプレーの選択に  ちょっと時間がかかっただけで
I'll get it right next time.
次はうまくやれるっての
It's okay.
大丈夫
I'm just not used to it,
まだ慣れてないだけだ
but it'll come to me in a bit.
もう少しやれば  しっくりくる
Yes... I've grown!
そう　俺は成長できてる
I can be an excellent forward who has a good overview of the pitch!
視野の広い　すげえフォワードに  俺は　なれる！
I hope so... eventually.
多分…
あとちょいで
But that Gino!
なのに　ジーノのヤツめ！
His eyes! He totally looked down on me.
俺をさげすむような  目で見やがって！
We're of the same age. What's with that attitude?
同い年のくせに
何だってんだ　あの態度は！
But when Gino acts like that, he usually doesn't give me the ball anymore...
でも　ああなった時のジーノって
なかなか俺へのパスが…
No, no!
Gino should have noticed it too!
ジーノも今に気づくはず
I've changed!
今までと違う　俺の姿に！
Right, manager?!
そうっスよね　達海監督
Whether it's resolve as a forward or other qualities...
フォワードの決心とか　何とかかんとか
I have them all!
今の俺には　ありますよ！
I'll show you!
ここで　それを見せつけたります！
I hit myself too hard...
強くたたきすぎた
I-Is he alright, that Natsuki...
だ…　大丈夫なんでしょうか  夏木は
Who knows?
さあねえ
I'm fine.
大丈夫　やれるさ
I can do this.
I realized today, before the match...
俺は気づいたんだ
今日の試合前　俺は
My... potential.
俺自身の伸びしろに
Alright, we're going to leave soon!
は～い
もうすぐ出発しますよ～
Please get on the bus as soon as you're ready.
準備できた人から　バスに  乗って下さい
Is everybody here?
全員いますか～？
Um, Yuri.
あのう…　有里ちゃん
Natsuki and, uhh, the manager aren't here.
夏木と
監督がいません
んもうっ！　どこ行ったのよ！
Where the hell did those two go?!
達海さんに　夏木さん！
The Osaka match is finally here. I'm fired up!
いよいよ大阪戦
テンション上がるぜ
But, in order to play well,
でも  いいプレーするためには
I'll have to do some image training before the match.
しっかり試合前に  イメージトレーニングしとかねえとな
Okay.
よし！
ほうっ！　りりしい  俺の姿！　調子は最高だ
There I am, looking cool. I'm in top form!
The ball goes to Gino, probably the most handsome guy after me.
ボールは  俺の次に男前のジーノ！
He's just acting cool, which is why I'm the number one!
男前っつっても
あいつは　カッコつけなだけだから
やっぱり  ホントの１番は俺だ！
Oops, that's irrelevant.
おっと…　このイメージは  関係ねえな
Focus, focus.
集中　集中
Ahh, there's my fast movement!
ああ　俺の　すばやい動きだし！
I'm aiming for an emphatic super volley!
狙いは　ダイナミックなスーパーボレーだ
And here comes the perfect pass from Gino!
そこに　ジーノからの  ドンピシャのパスが！
Wait, let's rewind that again...
もう１回　もう１回
巻き戻してと
As I bravely tussle at the front line, I found space to run into!
勇敢に前線で戦う俺
スペースへと飛び出した俺に  ジーノのパスが！
Gino passes!
Hey!
Image
いや　まだだ  　もう少し  下がって　もらいに行って…
No! I just need to rewind a bit to get it right.
What is this? Gino passing to me...
何てこった…  ジーノから俺へのパスが
I simply can't imagine it.
全くもって　イメージできねえ
Why?! Give me a pass, Gino!
何でだよ～！  パスくれよ　ジーノ！
I always thought you were weird,
へ…　変なヤツだとは  思ってたけど
お前って　ホント  気持ち悪いな  夏木
but you're just downright creepy, Natsuki.
は　は　恥ずかしい！  あ～　見られ…　あ～
T-This is so embarrassing! Don't look!
This is creepy too.
これまた気持ち悪い
It's not like this is totally new.
別に　今に始まった事じゃ  ないんですけど
なんか時々　俺に　パスよこさなく  なるんですよ…  ジーノの野郎
I realised that Gino has stopped passing the ball to me.
初めは　俺の　あふれるスター性への  嫉妬かと思いましたよ
At first, I thought he was just jealous of my great potential.
けど　違うんスよね
But that wasn't it.
あいつ　俺みたいな  すぐシュート打ちたがるフォワードは  嫌いなんスよ
He doesn't like forwards like me who just shoot on sight.
Even if I score a goal,
ゴール決めても
流れが良くなかったとか   美しくないとか  言いやがりますからね
he'll say that the flow wasn't good, that it lacks elegance or something.
まあ　しかたないんスけど…
Well, it can't be helped.
俺　下手っぴだし　パスの  出し手あっての　フォワードっスから
I'm just weak. I'm the type of forward who requires others to feed the ball to me.
ヘイ！　くれ　ジーノ！
Hey, here Gino!
よ～し！  そのまま行け　赤崎！
Great! Push forward, Akasaki!
That Gino! Blatantly making a disgruntled face.
ジーノのヤツ　あからさまに  嫌な顔しやがって
見てろってんだよ！
Just you watch!
I'll handle the ball carefully. The flow... Observe the flow!
ボールを大事に…　流れ　流れだ！
夏木　あのさあ
Hey, Natsuki, what's your definition of a forward?
お前にとって　フォワードって何？
フォ　フォワードってのは  バーンとシュートとか打ちまして  ドーンと　ゴールとか  決める人でして…
A-A forward is someone who shoots and scores goals.
俺にとっては　１１人の中で  相手ゴールの一番近くにいる選手
For me, a forward's the closest to the goal out of the 11 players.
そんだけだよ
Nothing more.
Huh?
In football, anyone can score a goal.
ゴールなら誰が決めたっていいのが  フットボールだ
フォワードが決めなきゃいけない  なんて　ルールはない
There's no rule that it has to be a forward.
とはいえ　さっきも言ったように
Though, like I just mentioned, the forward is the closest to the opponent's goal.
フォワードは相手のゴールの近くにいる
In Gino's case,
ジーノに限った話じゃない
The balls you receive at the front line...
お前が  前線で受けるボール
Well, they're all sent to you from the very hearts of your teammates.
そいつは  味方が必死になってつないできた  魂のこもったボールだ
お前にとって  そのボールって何だ？
What is that ball to you?
チームのボールか？　お前のボールか？
Is it the team's ball?
Or is it your ball?
夏木　お前には　フォワードとしての  決心が足りないよ
Natsuki, you lack the resolve as a forward.
そこんとこ　早めに  はっきりさせたほうがいい
You should make up your mind about that as soon as possible.
チームのボールか…　俺のボールか…
The team's ball?
Or mine?
そいつは…
That's...
Manager.
監督！
決めました  やってみますよ　俺
I've made up my mind. I'll try it!
Huh?
そのボールは　俺にとって…
To me, that ball is...
チャンスだ！
A chance! Pass it to Natsuki, Akasaki!
夏木に入れろ　赤崎！
小室さん…  五輪代表の　この人を抜けば
Komuro...
If I overcome this olympic player...
俺にも代表への資格が  あるって事だろ！
it'll mean that I'm qualified to be a national player, too!
よし！
Ok!
It went through!
通った！
But the angle's tight!
でも　コースがない！
Hey!
世良がフリーだ　夏木！
Sera is free. Natsuki!
回想　お前にとって  そのボールって何だ？
What is that ball to you?
The answer is obvious, Coach.
んなもん愚問です　監督
This is the team's ball.
こいつは　チームのボールっスよ
ゴールキーパーが防ぎ  ディフェンダーが奪い
The goalkeeper blocks the ball, the defenders secure it,
the midfielders battle the opponents to bring it all the way here.
ミッドフィルダーが相手と競り合いながら
ここまで　つないできた
It's the team's ball.
チームのボールっス
こいつを　俺のボール  なんて　言っちゃあならねえ
I can't say that this is my ball.
The forward is also a member of the team.
フォワードもチームの１人
It doesn't matter who scores the goal.
ゴールを決めるのは  チームの誰かであれば  いいんス
仲間を生かした　視野の広いプレー
I'm a forward with a good overview of the pitch
so I can fully utilise my teammate's potential.
そんなフォワードに俺は…
よっしゃ　ゴールキック！
Nice, goal kick. A gift.
もうけ　もうけ
Geez, what are you doing, Natsu?
まったく！  何やってんだよ　ナツさん！
おいおい　頼むぜ　夏木！
Hey! Come on, Natsuki!
あのバカ  勝つ気あんのか？
That idiot. Does he even want to win?
Macchan, make the subs warm up seriously.
松ちゃん　サブのアップ  本腰入れさせといて
Uh, sure. You're subbing him off?
え？…　はい  もう替えますか？
Natsuki can't do it.
夏木は駄目だ　何か  つまんねえ事になってやがる
It's starting to get boring.
If a player with doubts gets on the field,
迷いを持ったまま  ピッチに入ってる選手がいたら
the team will be infected with something bad.
チームに良くないものが  伝染しちまう
I misjudged him.
俺があいつを見誤った   俺のミスだよ
This is my mistake.
ETU's offense is destroying itself.
I suppose you can say that this is a result of our pressure.
At this rate we won't have anything to worry about.
We still have control of the game,
Dulfer.
Manager?
Oh, that's true, Sonoda. The ball's still in our court.
However, that's exactly why we should take the initiative!
If we rely on our lead and just sit back,
the flow of the game will change eventually.
In order to win, you have to be decisive.
Manager...
監督？
I can't see us scoring!
得点のにおいが  しなさすぎる
I think it's Natsuki.
やっぱり夏木じゃない？
Though he screws up a lot, his eccentricity's what makes things fun.
あいつ　ポカも多いけど
わけわかんないとこが  面白いじゃん
Yeah.
But today, watching Natsuki isn't fun at all.
でもさ　今日の夏木はさ  何か見ててもワクワクしないよね
何か見ててもワクワクしないよね
Forward...
フォワードなんてさ  ただのポジションの名前だよ
that's just a name for a position.
Yes?
It's pretty common for a forward to get criticized if he doesn't score.
よく　フォワードが点取んないと  たたかれるけどさ
But I think that's a stupid concept.
その考えって安易だと思うんだ
Football's compromising.
フットボールは　もっと自由だ
Uh, yeah...
But you know, every once in a while,
けどね　たまにいるんだ
there is a forward who's self-centred.
エゴイストになれるフォワードってのが
For instance,
例えば　前線まで味方が運んできた  ボールがあるとする
there is a ball that your teammates carried all the way to the front lines.
Is this ball the team's ball or the forward's?
このボールはチームのものか  フォワードのものか
So whose is it, Macchan?
どっち？　松ちゃん
え？…　え～と
Uh... it's the team's ball...
チームの…　ボールです
う～ん…　正解
Correct.
だよね
It should be.
Most players will answer that way. It's pretty obvious.
ほとんどの選手は　そう答えるよ
だって当たり前の事なんだから
But an egoist is different.
でも　エゴイストは違う
They have the guts to think that though it's the team's ball,
そいつは  チームのボールだと分かった上で
it's also his ball.
自分のボールだと思い込める  度胸がある
To be able to shoulder the hopes of your teammates and yet play for yourself at the same time...
味方の思いを背負い切って  自分のためにプレーできるか
That is the resolve of an egoistic forward.
それが　エゴイスティックなフォワードとしての  決心だよ
A forward like that is strong.
そういうフォワードは強いよ
Because they have the guts to request for the ball even after they've failed.
度胸があるから　しくじっても  何度でもパスを要求する
They will try to shoot from anywhere.
どこからでもシュートを狙う
That's why they will score more often.
だからゴールも量産される
I thought that Natsuki might be of that type,
夏木も  そういうタイプかと思ったんだけど
but if he was intimidated by Gino that easily,
ジーノのプレッシャーが  超えられないようじゃ
that means that he isn't.
そういうタイプじゃ  なかったって事だ
あ…　後半　もう１０分  過ぎちゃったのか
It's already 10 minutes into the 2nd half... It's been tough.
参ったな
I promised the manager...
実は監督と　３点目は　開始１０分  までにって約束していたんだ
that we'd get our 3rd goal within 10 minutes.
相変わらず　なめた野郎だ！
This guy's always so cocky.
I think it's time to fulfill our promise...
そろそろ  約束を果たしに行こうか
Kubotan!
クボタン！
It's Kubota!
窪田だ！
スギ！
Sugie!
さて　果たして  前半同様　後半も輝けるかな？
Now, can you shine in the second half like you did in the first, Monsieur Kubota?
ムッシュ　クボタ
え～っと…  うん　３点目　３点目だ
The 3rd goal. 3rd goal.
Dulfer said that we'd win if we get 3 goals.
ダルファー監督も言っていた
３点目取れば　ウチが勝つって
I've enjoyed myself a lot today.
せっかく  楽しくプレーできてるんだ
It's been so much fun that we simply have to win.
せっかくだもの  勝たなくては
畑に通った！
It went to Hatake!
Well done, Kubo! Nice pass!
ようやった　クボ！  ナイスパスや！
わはっ
Hatake is fast!
畑　速え！
Stop him, Ishihama!
止めろ　石浜！
Come on, Hatake!
Hey, watch it!
痛えな　コラ！
They'll play it to Hauer, Kuroda! Block his movement!
ハウアーで来るぞ　黒田！
動き封じろ！
It's Shimura!
志村だ！
You really think so?!
させるかよ！
Great, that's our Murakoshi!
よっしゃ～！  さすが村越さん！
Koshi!
コシさん！
Sera!
世良！
Go, counter!
行け　カウンター！
行け～！  村越～！
You morons! I didn't have my turn yet!
アホか！  俺　まだ絡んでへんやろ！
Nice, Katayama!
ナイス片山！
That's right, Osaka's attacks don't end that easily!
そや！　大阪の攻撃は  そう簡単に終わらへんで！
Yup, we still have time.
うん　時間は　まだある
Don't let him go, stop him!
行かせるな！　止めろ～！
The fun will continue.
楽しい時間は　まだ続くんだ
I'm so happy while we're attacking.
幸せだなあ  攻撃してる　この瞬間
A forward who's allowed to attack this much really has it all.
たくさん攻撃できるフォワードって  やっぱり　なんとも贅沢だ
He got past Sugie!
杉江　抜かれた！
Go, Kubota!
Score, Kubota!
I have to thank Dulfer for converting me to a forward.
ダルファー監督に  お礼を言わなくては
フォワードにコンバートしてくれた  ダルファー監督に　３点目を取って
I'll score the 3rd goal to thank him for that!
お礼を…
T-Tsubaki! Nice steal!
椿～！
ナイスカット～！
Uh.. um...
あ…　え～っと…  あの　まだ…
Not yet...
Go, Tsubaki!
行け　椿！
Show them your blistering pace!
お前の足　見せつけてやれ
Go, Tsubaki! Run through!
よ～し　行け　椿！
ぶっちぎれ～！
At least one...
１つでも…
I have to create at least one chance!
１つでもチャンスを作んないと
What's that?
何だ　あれ？  まるで風みたいだ
He's like the wind. Isn't he my age?
あの人　確か  同い年じゃなかったっけ？
おっと　いけない
Oh no, I have to chase him.
追わなくては
Alright, go!
よし　行け！
Hiraga, stop him in the centre!
平賀！
Hiraga!
It's okay, we have enough people.
大丈夫だ   人数は足りてる
Just come, I'll take it from you here!
直接来い！
この位置で奪ってやる
Keep going like that, Baki.
そのまま行くがいいさ  バッキー
I'm sure you'll get through. Well, that's because of my sacrifice.
きっと抜けるよ
ま　それも僕の犠牲が  あったからこそなんだけど
No way!
そんな！
あ　ついていけない！
He can't keep up!
He got past Hiraga! This is our chance!
平賀　振り切った！  チャンスだ～！
Great! Continue down and cut it back, Tsubaki!
おっしゃ～！  そのまま行って　クロスに上げろ　椿
うん？　何だ　何だ　おい！
What's this, what's this?
Am I still worrying about that tight angle from before?
まだ　さっきのコースの事が  気になってんのか？  打ったところで
Even if I had shot, it wouldn't have gone in. It was too tight.
入りゃしなかったって   あんなギリギリのコース
Forget about it. Being a forward is not just about shooting.
切り替えろ 　何でもかんでも  シュートを打つのが　フォワードじゃねえ
I injured myself because I kept trying crazy shots.
無茶なシュートばっか打ってきたから  あんなケガをしたんじゃないか
It took me 8 months to get back here.
ここに戻るまで８か月かかった
I don't want to experience that again!
あんな思いは　もうたくさんだ！
But am I enjoying the match?
だけど　俺  この試合　楽しめてる？
You idiot! You don't have time to worry about that!
バカ野郎！　そんな脳天気な事  言ってられっか！
I'm a player! I have to contribute to my team at all times!
俺は選手だぞ
どんな形であれ  チームに貢献するのが仕事だ
It doesn't matter what I want to do.
俺が　どうしたいかなんて…
I told you guys.
俺　言ったろ   大事なのは　お前らが  この試合を  面白がれるかどうかだって
The important thing is whether you guys can enjoy the match.
Sera's close!
世良　ニアだ！
Go, Tsubaki!
上げろ　椿～！
Natsu!
ナツさん！
Shoot already, Natsuki!
いいかげん打てよ　夏木
Follow your instinct! You're a striker, aren't you?!
本能を貫けよ！  ストライカーだろ　お前は！
Ah, so close!
ぐあ～っ　惜しい！
It's not over, follow up!
まだだ！　詰めろ！
That's not far enough, get it up front!
クリア　半端だ！  前に出せ　前！
Nice, Akasaki!
よしっ　赤崎！
Akasaki! Let me shoot!
赤崎　俺に打たせろ！
It's Natsuki! Lima, block Natsuki!
夏木だ！  夏木を抑えろ　リマ！
う！ しまっ…
Oh shi-
You've got find the way to believe
carry on and carry on
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say 「never look back」
I'll say “never look back”
追い風を待って
oikaze o matte
Wait for the tailwind
そうchanceをのがすなら
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
自分が風になれ no fears no tears
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
no tears,Yes Let it go！
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
限界追い越せ
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
行け キツイほど
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
heart in red
Go on！(Stay cool！）
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
Go on！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
あすは見えない だから
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
It's time to go
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
やめられない
Get tough!
Get tough！Get tough！ Get tough！
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
共に乗り越えて 行け
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
見えるか It's daybreak there
mieruka It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
Go on！(Stay cool！) Go on！(We'll go！)
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
We'll go!
予測できないだから
yosoku dekinai dakara
The future is unpredictable
It's time to go
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
止められない
20 minutes left. ETU's in for a rough time.
The excellent Kubota's getting subbed.
It's just as we planned!
How much stamina does this guy have?!